Erik Sundell

erik.sundell87@gmail.com +46 (0) 737 416629 Ivar Vidfamnes gata 4, 126 52 Hägersten

PERSONAL STATEMENT

I am a versatile, hands-on 26 years old developer with 5 years of experience working on a variety of small projects from conception to delivery. I am conversant in a wide range of technologies – most notably C# and web development – and follow the latest industry trends with great interest. My approach is methodical but creative, and I always look to code to the highest standards possible. I am a confident communicator and I am comfortable working either independently or as part of a team.

KEY SKILLS

- Angular, Typescript, Javascript, jQuery
- C#, .NET Framework 4.6
- ASP.NET MVC 2, 3, 4 & 5
- HTML5, CSS3, SASS, Responsive Web Design
- T-SQL, MySQL, MS SQL Server
- nUnit, Specflow, Jasmine.js
- GIT, Subversion, TFS
- NODE.js, Gulp, Karma
- Teamcity, Octopus deploy

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

ASP.NET C# Developer

H&M IT Buying & Production office | Stockholm, Sweden | Nov 2015 – Oct 2016

- Delivering an internal website that would harmonize all sellprices on each country and channel
- Developing advanced frontend grid systems using Angular and agGrid
- Being responsible for environmental matters such as Teamcity builds, git branching,
 Powershell scripting and deployments using Octopus deploy
- Creating maintainable Javascript using Typescript with realtime transpilation
- Designing responsive, minimalistic user interfaces using Bootstrap and SASS
- Being part of the whole project, including on-time shipping to production

Reference:

Ann Thulstrup, Group manager. | +46 8 5176 2591 | Ann.Thulstrup@hm.com

C# Developer

H&M IT Buying & Production office | Stockholm, Sweden | Feb 2015 – Nov 2015

- Delivering a windows desktop app that would be utilized by designers to overview product assortment
- Pushing the limits of WPF in order to create rich user experiences for the end users
- Being part of the whole project, including on-time shipping to production
- Taking an active part in the designing and decision-making regarding architectural matters within the code
- Coding using a test-first approach that included unit tests, specflow tests and integration tests

Reference:

Ann Thulstrup, Group manager. | +46 8 5176 2591 | Ann.Thulstrup@hm.com

ASP.NET C# Developer

Oakton consulting | Melbourne VIC, Australia | Jun 2014 - Dec 2014

- Creating a public website for Australia's largest provider of salary packaging
- Connecting Umbraco (open source CMS) to an ASP.NET MVC web application in order to make the site content fully dynamic
- Developing the website using a strict mobile-first approach
- Taking an active part in the rollout process
- Using jQuery mobile in order to create a rich user experience

Reference:

David Bary, Chief Architect. | - | -

C# Developer

H&M IT Buying & Production office | Stockholm, Sweden | May 2013 - Feb 2014

- Writing advanced unit- and integration tests that ensure code quality and high modularity between the various components in the system
- Working with SCRUM in a team with distributed workforce, having some team members in Bangalore, India
- Taking an active role in the full development life-cycle
- Liaising with various service providers
- Supporting junior members of the team, providing ongoing advice and guidance

Reference:

Peter Pernäng, Group Manager. | +46 (0) 72 173 1052 | Peter.Pernang@hm.com

ASP.NET C# Developer

H&M IT Finance & Accounting office | Stockholm, Sweden | Sep 2011 - May 2013

- Creating reports out of large datasets in SQL Server 2008/2010 and presenting the content in a complex web UI using HTML5 and jQuery
- Developing responsive web sites using frameworks/libraries such as Bootstrap, Modernizr.js and Respond.js
- Creating a customized build environment for continuous integration using TeamCity
- Designing and developing a SOA-based solution used for tallying tax rates that are generated by different tax calculation services in the cloud
- Developing multi-threaded C# applications that interfaced with point of sales (electronic fund transfer - EFT) solutions to generate bookkeeping data for sales transactions

Reference:

Linus Bengtsson, Group Manager. | +46 (0) 73 3233296 | Linus.Bengtsson@hm.com

Operator

Niscayah emergency service center | Stockholm, Sweden | Jun 2009 – Aug 2011 (part-time while studying)

- Receiving calls from customers
- Programming alarm detectors

Reference:

Åsa Persson, Manager. | +46 (0) 70 3145475

Office janitor

The Swedish Crime Victim Compensation and Support Authority | Umeå, Sweden | Aug 2006 – Jun 2008

- Ordering office supplies and maintaining contact with suppliers
- Being responsible for mail processing and delivery services
- Performing simple repairs

Reference:

Margareta Bergström, General Director | +46 (0) 90 172000

EDUCATION

Uppsala University, Uppsala, Sweden, Sep 2009 – Jun 2011 Degree of Bachelor of Social Science, focusing on Information Systems

Thesis: Analyzing Test-driven development - a qualitative study of TDD's impacts on software design

See separate document for a list of all courses

Bonus courses

- Business studies,30 credits (one semester of full-time studies)
 - -Accounting, 15 credits
 - -Marketing and Organisation, 15 credits
- Programming in .NET: Advanced, 7,5 credits
- Responsive webdesign, 7.5 credits
- Webdesign with JavaScript and the Document Object Model, 7,5 credits
- CSS based webdesign, 7,5 credits
- Markup languages and Stylesheets, 7,5 credits

Dragonskolan High School, Umeå, Sweden *Natural science programme, Sep 2003 – Jun 200*6

NON-PROFIT WORK EXPERIENCE AND OTHER QUALITIES

- Engaged in the Information Science Student Union throughout most of my studies. Features include being part of the Economy Committee where I had a key role in the planning of events together with our business sponsors
- Buddy for new Information Science students during orientation weeks in Uppsala

LANGUAGE, INTERESTS AND OTHER

- Language Proficiency: Fluent in English and Swedish. Basic French
- Interests: Sports especially soccer and running, travelling, playing guitar and hang out with friends
- Driving license: Full, clearAvailability: Immediately